<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Application Security on JakobTheDev | Jakob Pennington</title>
    <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/categories/application-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Application Security on JakobTheDev | Jakob Pennington</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jakobthe.dev/images/profile.png</url>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/images/profile.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 15:45:00 +1030</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jakobthe.dev/categories/application-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building hacking tools in Windows using Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/building-hacking-tools-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/building-hacking-tools-docker/</guid>
      <description>Something that I have struggled with in the past as a software developer turned penetration tester is the fact that I use two operating systems on a daily basis, and this sometimes causes friction in my workflow.
Note: I really don’t intend or want this to be a discussion of the merits of one OS or IDE compared with another. I use the tools that I am familiar and productive with, and it’s totally cool if you use something different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Docker containers replace VMs for bug bounty hunters and penetration testers?</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/docker-for-pentesters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/docker-for-pentesters/</guid>
      <description>There were many things to consider, and we may talk about some of those things in the future, but the aspect of penetration testing I want to talk about today is the infrastructure we use to conduct a penetration test.
Note: With a few minor exceptions, the same thought process applies for bug bounty hunting. If that’s more your thing, feel free to sed s/penetration testing/bug bounty hunting/g.
What do we need from our infrastructure?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shifting Left: DevSecOps as an Approach to Building Secure Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/shifting-left/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/shifting-left/</guid>
      <description>Why traditional security testing should not be the core of your application security program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eight Phases of a DevOps Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/eight-phases-devops-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/eight-phases-devops-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Let’s break down the phases of a DevOps pipeline and clarify some common terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is DevOps?</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/what-is-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/what-is-devops/</guid>
      <description>The simplest introduction to DevOps and the benefits it can provide to your organisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting XSS via Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/exploiting-xss-via-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/exploiting-xss-via-markdown/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across a web application in which I was able to exploit a Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) vulnerability through a markdown editor and rendering package. It was the first time I had come across this type of vulnerability, and I found it particularly interesting because it allowed me to bypass multiple layers of XSS filtering that was implemented in the application. Here’s a short article on how I came across the vulnerability and set about crafting an exploit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking into Encrypted iPhone Backups</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/breaking-into-iphone-backups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/breaking-into-iphone-backups/</guid>
      <description>The day that being a hacker made me feel like a hero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Notifications to your AWS CI/CD Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/codepipeline-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/codepipeline-notifications/</guid>
      <description>This post is Part 3 in a 🤷-Part series on CI/CD in AWS. Go check out my other posts to see how we got here:
Part 1: Deploy a Single-Page Application (SPA) to AWS
Part 2: Automated Build / Deploy with AWS CodePipeline
In the last post, we set up a simple CI/CD pipeline that deploys our codebase into production each time new code is merged into the production codebase. This is great, but once we kick off a build we have two options:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Build / Deploy with AWS CodePipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/aws-codepipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/aws-codepipeline/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I showed how you can deploy a Single Page Application to AWS using AWS’ S3, CloudFront and Route 53. This post picks up where the last one left off, so if you haven’t read it, go check it out!
This time, we’ll be improving our DevOps by building a basic CI/CD pipeline. Since we’re already using AWS to host our site, it makes sense to keep using their services since they do integrate well together (That’s how they get you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Single Page Application (SPA) to AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/deploy-spa-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/deploy-spa-aws/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I made a simple personal website — a hub for my online presences and a place to share my personal projects. I developed the site using the Angular CLI, and when it came time to host the site, I chose AWS since my domain was already set up in Route 53. Overall, the process of building the application and hosting it on AWS was a fairly simple one (you could probably set the whole thing up in about an hour), but there were a couple of gotchyas that prompted me to write down the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minifying XSS</title>
      <link>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/minifying-xss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 15:45:00 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jakobthe.dev/posts/minifying-xss/</guid>
      <description>How I bypassed Cross-Site Scripting sanitisation in fewer than 20 characters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
